<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lance Lafontaine</title>
    <description>Lance Lafontaine's Internet Home.</description>
    <link>http://lancelafontaine.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://lancelafontaine.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>A Beginner's Cheat Sheet to Vim.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past month or so, I have been making the gradual switch from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_%28text_editor%29&quot;&gt;vim&lt;/a&gt; after reading about its supposed increase in efficency. Although I had been warned of vim's steep learning curve, I actually found the transition to be rather smooth, and I'm now feeling about as comfortable with it as I did with ST2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that really helped me internalize vim's plethora of commands and shortcuts was making my own cheatsheet. I would suggest you do the same, but if you want to cheat &lt;em&gt;(pun)&lt;/em&gt; and save yourself some time, you can take a look at what I've made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;
  width:800px;
  height:620px;
  border-radius: 5px;
  background:#ccc;
  padding:10px;
  position:relative;
  margin:auto &quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://docs.google.com/viewer?url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Flancelafontaine%2Fvim-cheatsheet%2Fraw%2Fmaster%2Fvimcheatsheet.pdf&amp;embedded=true&quot; width=&quot;780&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; style=&quot;border: none;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download it in PDF format &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lancelafontaine/vim-cheatsheet/raw/master/vimcheatsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, as well as view the LaTeX code used to make the document in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lancelafontaine/vim-cheatsheet&quot;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://lancelafontaine.github.io//2015/01/13/beginner-vim-cheat-sheet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lancelafontaine.github.io//2015/01/13/beginner-vim-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello, world! A first post from a new developer.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Lance Lafontaine and I am a software engineering student at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.concordia.ca/&quot;&gt;Concordia University&lt;/a&gt; in Montreal, Canada. I love full-stack web dev, Linux and Unix operating systems, and everything about open source and startups.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Why software, you ask? Believe it or not, my lifelong coding quest began with ...&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h2&gt;DNA and Proteins.&lt;/h2&gt;




&lt;p&gt; Once upon a time, I was studying in &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/jubr4FR.jpg&quot;&gt;molecular biology&lt;/a&gt;. I had decided to pursue my studies in the field after my introduction to it in college. The content was rather interesting, and I was pretty good at memorizing biochemical reactions and cellular functions and structures.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to 2013. I was working in a synthetic biology lab for my &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lancelafontaine/undergraduate-biology-thesis&quot;&gt;undergraduate thesis&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Genetically_Engineered_Machine&quot;&gt;iGEM team&lt;/a&gt; and I quickly realized that &lt;em&gt;lab work was not for me&lt;/em&gt;. Given my knowledge set at the time, I took a few bioinformatics and computational biology courses, as well as an introductory Java course, COMP248.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt; The computational biology course with &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://web.chem.ucsb.edu/~molvisual/Img/143/kissingloop_bindsite_front_withbonds.png&quot;&gt;PyMoL&lt;/a&gt; was fun, but &lt;strong&gt;Java instantly blew me away&lt;/strong&gt;. The logic kept me so engaged. Compiling was just so &lt;em&gt;gratifying&lt;/em&gt;. COMP248 was more fulfilling to me than any other I had taken over the previous three years: I had gained the seemingly-magical power to tell my computer to do complex tasks, &lt;em&gt;and it obeyed me without question&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;But with great power comes great responsibility. The change in career paths was a difficult realization to come to terms with, especially after working so hard for an entire degree's worth, but I couldn't deny that &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://thisdeveloperslife.com/&quot;&gt;this developer's life&lt;/a&gt; was for me.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;After considering some options that were available to me (like an Independent Master's in Bioinformatics), I decided to look into another Bachelor's degree because it would provide me with a stronger foundation in computer science as well as the possibility for paid internships to help me finance my studies. I ended up applying for the Software Engineering Co-op program at Concordia and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://cdn1.hubspot.com/hub/245581/file-317911732.jpg&quot;&gt;got in&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt; And now here I am, enjoying my first semester in the new program. There are &lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; new concepts, languages, and technologies to learn, but I'm extremely happy with my current situation, and that is truly what matters most to me.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;I will be updating this blog semi-regularly provided that coursework doesn't get in the way, so be sure to check back here for new blog posts, rants, milestones, stories and/or opinionated thoughts along the way to my developer path. I'd love to hear from you too: leave a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://lancelafontaine.github.io//2014/11/06/A-first-post-some-dummy-text/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://lancelafontaine.github.io//2014/11/06/A-first-post-some-dummy-text/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>